Guide to the Maritime History Collection PR 100
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Boxed Files
  - Subseries I.4: Other Ships & Ship Details
    Other Ships & Ship Details includes images of barges, motor ships, lightships, rowboats and tugboats. Photographs of the Swedish American liners MS Gripsholm and MS Kungsholm include interior views. Images on board unidentified ships include both naval and civilian ships, on deck and below. Ship plans are reproductions, several for ferryboats, including the Artic, Easton and J.M. Waterbury. Reproductions of Robert Fulton plans show various steamboat improvements. Relics contain mainly photographs, including an image of the stairs from the steamer Henry Clay, several decorative carvings removed from steamships and a clipping showing boatswain's calls. One interesting relic is a label from a crate salvaged from the wreck of the steamship Atlantic in 1873. Images of sailmaking include a photograph of a New Jersey sail and rigging loft and a clipping of a sailmaker's bench, showing the tools of the trade.
    - Miscellaneous Ships- Various Types (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Ferries & Lighters A-I (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Ferries & Lighters- City of Sacramento (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Ferries & Lighters J-Z (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Feries & Lighters- Warwick (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Ferries & Lighters- Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Ferries & Lighters- New Jersey Central Railroad (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Motor Ships A-Z (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Motor Ships- MS Gripsholm (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Motor Ships- MS Kungsholm (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Rowboats & Rafts (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Tugboats (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified Ships- Images on Board (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Plans, Ship & Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Misc. Plans by Robert Fulton (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Billethead & Figurehead (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Maritime Art (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Relics (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Sailmaking (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Ships- Albumen Prints (Box 17)
  - Subseries I.5: Views
    Views is comprised of images of both United States and foreign locations. Miscellaneous views are varied, from a souvenir set of images of New York City to a group of postcards showing inventor John Ericsson's home in Langbanshyttan, Sweden.
    - General Views- Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Monuments & Memorials (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Shipyards & Dry Docks (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Harbor/Water Views- Foreign Misc. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Harbor/Water Views- England (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Harbor/Water Views- France (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Harbor/Water Views- The Netherlands (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Harbor/Water Views- United States (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Harbor/Water Views- New York City (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Harbor/Water Views- Unidentified (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of New York Harbor, taken by J.G.M. Glessner 1892 (Box 17)
  - Subseries I.6: Clippings, Papers & Ephemera
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Ferries (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hudson River Day Line (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Naval Ships (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - USS Constitution (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Passenger and Cargo Lines (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - People (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Journals & Newsletters (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.7: Events
    Naval Battles is comprised of images of varioyus wars and battles at sea. The bulk of this material surrounds battles during the War of 1812.
    - Events-Celebrations
      See also Box 16, Columbian Naval Review
      - Columbian Naval Review 1893, Albumen Prints (Box 16)
      - Kiel Canal Opening 1895 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Hudson-Fulton Celebration 1909 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Launching the USS J. William Ditter 1944 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Commissioning of the USS Goodrich 1945 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Events- Naval Battles
      - Revolutionary War (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Quasi War with France (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Quasi War with France USS Constellation & L'Insurgente (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Barbary Wars (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - War of 1812 Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - War of 1812- Attack of Fort Oswego (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - War of 1812- Battle of Lake Erie (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - War of 1812- Chesapeake & HMS Shannon (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - War of 1812- USS Constitution & the Guerriere (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - War of 1812- USS Constitution & the Java (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - War of 1812- USS Enterprise & HMS Boxer (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - War of 1812- USS President & HMS Endymion (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - War of 1812- USS United States & British Frigate Macedonian (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - War of 1812- USS Wasp & HMS Frolic (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Civil War- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Civil War- Battle of Mobile Bay (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Civil War- Battle at New Orleans (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Civil War- USS Kearsage & CSS Alabama (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - USS St. Lawrence & Privateer Petrel (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Spanish American War (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Misc. Battles & Wars- At Sea (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Misc. Battles & Wars- On Land (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Privateers (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Events- Miscellaneous
      - Expeditions (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Races (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Race Week, Larchmont Yacht Club 1902 (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Shipwrecks & Fires (Box 11, Folder 31)
        See also, Box 17 - Merrit & Chapman Derrick & Wrecking Co.
      - Whaling (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Misc. & Unidentified Events (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Shipwrecks- Merritt & Chapman Derrick & Wrecking Co., Photographs (Box 17)
  - Subseries I.9: Portraits
    - A, general (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes portraits of Frank C. Adams, U.S.N., James M. Adams, John Adams, Captain James Alden, William Henry Allen Esq., Commander Daniel Ammen, John A. Andrew, Chester A. Arthur and Major General C.C. Augur.
    - Ba-Bl, general (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Includes portraits of Lieutenant George M. Bache, Commodore O.C. Badger, Captain Charles H. Balch, Rear Admiral G.B. Balch, U.S.N., Acting Lietuenant Charles H. Baldwin, Commander J.P. Bankhead, Josiah Barker, George Bancroff, Rear Admiral Albert S. Barker, General Francis Barlow, Lieutenant Commander George E. Belknap, George M. Bibb, Mrs. Mary A. Bickerdyke, N.H. Bidwell, Capt. A. Bielaski, Commodore Abraham Bigelow, The Hon. John Bigelow, William Bigler, Commodore Blake and Blackbeard the pirate.
    - Bailey, Theodorus (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bainbridge, William (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Barnes, James (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Barnes, John S. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Barney, Joshua (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Barry, John (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Biddle, A-Z (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Blake, Robert (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Blakely, Johnston (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Bo-Bu, general (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Includes images of Charles F. Boggs, General Bosquet, Nathaniel Bowditch, Lieutenant Commander D.L. Braine, Lieutenant Commander K. Randolph Breese, Horatio Bridge, Dr. H.S. Bristol, S.B. Brittan Jr., J.L. Broome, Edwin Tracy Brower, Dr. John Brown, Captain Isaac N. Brown, Rear Admiral Willard Herbert Brownson, Major General Brown, Commodore Franklin Buchanan and Captain James D. Bulloch.
    - Ca-Co, general (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Includes portraits of C.H.B. Caldwell, Rear Admiral W.B. Caperton, Silas Casey, Captin John Cassin, Lieutenant Commder Chandler, Rear Admiral Ralph Chandler, Hon. S. P. Chase, Isaac Chauncey, Honorable Joseph H. Choate, Rear Admiral Joseph B. Coghlan,Lieutenant Commander Augustus P. Cooke, Commander James W. Cooke, Commander George H. Cooper, Commander J.J. Cornwell and William Sitgreaves Cox.
    - Cooper, James Fennimore (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Cr-D, general (Box 13, Folder 15)
      Includes portraits of William Harris Crawford, Commander B.G. Crowmwell, Rear Admiral Pierce Crosby, Benjamin William Crowninshield, William E. Curtis, Lieutenant William B. Cushing, General Custer and Paymaster General Cutter.
    - Davies, Walter Rappelya (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Decatur, Stephen (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - E, general (Box 13, Folder 18)
      Includes portraits of Henry Eagle, General Charles Ellett, Oliver Ellsworth, Lieutenant Commander Earl English and Captain Edward England.
    - Evans, Robley D. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - F, general (Box 13, Folder 20)
      Includes portraits of L.E. Fagan, Commander D.M.N. Fairfax, Rear Admiral Arthur P. Fairfield, Commodore N.H. Farquhar, William Faxon, Lieutenant Commander Charles W. Flussen, Fleet Surgeon J.W. Foltz, R.B. Forbes, Commander French Forrest, Gustavus V. Fox, Charles Fox, John Franklin, James Fox and Robert Fulton.
    - Farragut, David Glasgow (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Foote, Andrew Hull (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Ga-Go, general (Box 13, Folder 23)
      Includes portraits of Major General Edmund P. Gaines, Major General J.A. Garfield, Brigadier General Ernest A. Garlington, William Gaston, General Horatio Gates, Captain H.R.H. The Duke of York, Elbridge Gerry, Commander James P. Gerry, Rear Admiral Bancroft Gherardi, Jasper W. Gilbert, Quincy Adams Gillmore, Stephen Girard, Mordecai Gist, Captain O.S. Glisson, Edward Lawrence Godkin, Commander S.W. Godon, Parke Godwin and Rear Admiral Louis M. Goldsborough.
    - Gr-Gz, general (Box 13, Folder 24)
      Includes images of General A.W. Greely, Captain J.H. Green, Lietenant Samuel Daniel Greene, Lieutenant Commander James A. Greer, General Charles Griffin, Martin I.J. Griffin, John Grimball, James Guthrie and Lieutenant Commander William Gwin.
    - Grant, Ulysses S. (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - H, general (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Includes images of Alexander Hamilton, Mrs. John Hancock, Walter Harris, Major General Harrison, William Henry Harrison, Edward Henry Harriman, Charles H. Haswell, R.B. Hayes, John Dandridge Henley, Infante Don Henrique, John Augustus, Lord Hervey, Thomas Heyward Jr., Captain George N. Hollins, Lieutenant Richmond Pearson Hobson, General O.O. Howard, Commander J.C. Howell, Commander William L. Hudson, Colonel Humphreys, David Humphreys and Samuel A. Huntington.
    - Hopkins, Esek (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Hull, Isaac (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - I-K, general (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Includes portraits of John Irwin, Benjamin Franklin Isherwood, Amos Kendall, J.P. Kennedy, James Kent, Hon. Sir Harry Keppel, Rufus King, Tadeusz Kosciuszko and Augustatus Kuningam.
    - Jones, John Paul (Box 14, Folder 5)
      See also John Paul Jones Scrapbook box 20
    - John Paul Jones, framed engraved portrait and hair with accompanying letter from Howard Beisel (Box 19)
    - L, general (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Includes portraits of the Marquis de Lafayette, General John Lamb, Rear Admiral Joseph Lanman, Abbott Lawrence, John Lenthall, Reverend Noah Levings, Uriah P. Levy, Francis Lewis, Philip Livingston, Commodore John Collins Long, John Davis Long, Captain George Lowther, Admiral Stephen Bleecker Luce, Rev. S. Luckey and Thomas Lynch Jr.
    - Laurence, James (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Lee, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Includes portraits of Col. Henry Lee, Arthur Lee and General Robert E. Lee.
    - LeRoy, William E. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Lincoln, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Includes portraits of Abraham Lincoln, Benjamin Lincoln and Levi Lincoln.
    - Mc, general (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Includes portraits of Lieutenant Edward R. McCall, Lieutenant Commander Edward Yorke McCauley, General George B. McClellan, Lieutenant Roderick S. McCook, William McKinley, Commander Charles F. McIntosh, Captain Lachlan McIntosh and Captain McNeal.
    - M, general (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Includes portraits of Alexander Slidell Mackenzie, James Madison, Captain Maffitt, Admiral Mahan, Stephen R. Mallory, Ambrose Marechal, General John H. Martindale, Commander Charles C. Marsh, Fleet Surgeon George Maulsby, Matthew Fontaine Maury, George G. Meade, Rear Admiral Richard W. Meade, E.T. Merrick, Victor H. Metcalf, Arthur Middleton, Commander John K. Mitchell, Dr. S. Weir Mitchell, James Monroe, Richard Montgomery, Samuel F.B. Morse, Col. Moseley, Captain James Mugford and Commander R. Madison Mullany.
    - Macdonough, Thomas (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Morgan, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Includes portraits of Charles W. Morgan, Brigadier Genereal Daniel Morgan, Sir Henry Morgan and William F. Morgan.
    - Morris, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 15)
      Includes portraits of Captain Charles Morris, Lieutenant George U. Morris, Lewis Morris and Mrs. Robert Morris.
    - N-O, general (Box 14, Folder 16)
      Includes portraits of Nicholas Emperor of Russia, Commander J.H.A. Nicholson, Admiral Sir Charles Napier, Napoleon III, Professor Charles Elliot Norton, Captain Jonathan S. Odell, John Ogilvie and James Edward Oglethorpe.
    - P, general (Box 14, Folder 17)
      Includes portraits of William Paca, Robert Treat Paine, Commander James S. Palmer, Commander Foxall A. Parker, Lieutenant Commander James Parker, Lieutenant Commander William Harwar Parker, Omar Pasha, Lieutenant Daniel T. Patterson, Sir Richard Pearson, D.C. Pennell, C.H. Pennington, George Hamilton Perkins, T.S. Phelps, Lieutenant Commander S. Ledyard Phelps, Rear Admiral John W. Philip, General Andrew Pickens, Zebulon M. Pike, General C.C. Pinckney, Fleet Surgeon Ninian Pinkney, William Pinkney, Pocahontas and Lieutenant Samuel W. Preston.
    - Paulding, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 18)
      Includes portraits of Commander Hiram Paulding, J.K. Paulding and Lieutenant Leonard Paulding.
    - Pierce, Franklin (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Preble, Edward (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Porter, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 21)
      Includes portraits of Commodore Porter, Lieutenant Benjamin H. Porter, Carlisle P. Porter, Col. Peter Porter and General Horace Porter.
    - Porter, David D. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Porter, David, Sr. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Porter, William D. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Q, general (Box 14, Folder 25)
      Includes portraits of Lieutenant Commander S.P. Quackenbush and Lieutenant W.W. Queen.
    - R, general (Box 14, Folder 26)
      Includes portraits of Commodore William Radford, Rear Admiral F.M. Ramsay, John Randolph, George Read, Commander Abner Reed, George C. Remey, Lieutenant Joseph Warren Revere, Commander A.C. Rhind, James C. Rice, Captain Charles G. Ridgely, Captain C. Ringold, Captain Bartholomew Roberts, George M. Robeson, Commander James H. Rochelle, Captain Ell B. Rockwell, Rear Admiral Roe, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Elihu Root, John Henry Rowland and Benjamin Rush.
    - Rodgers, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 27)
      Includes portraits of John Rodgers, Rear Admiral C.R.P. Rodgers, Commander George H. Rodgers and Commodore Rodgers.
    - Rowan, Stephen C. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Sa-Sh, general (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Includes portraits of Major General Arthur St. Clair, Gurdon Saltonstall, Admiral William T. Sampson, John Savage, Oscar G. Sawyer, Commodore James S. Schenck, Commander W.S. Schley, Walter K. Scofield, Major General Winfield Scott, Major General John Sedgwick, John Senthall, Col. Edwin Shaw, Philip H. Sheridan, Edwin A. Sherman, William T. Sherman, Commander James W. Shirk and Commander John T. Shubrick.
    - Schuyler, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Semmes, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Includes images of Lieutenant A.A. Semmes and Admiral Raphael Semmes.
    - Si-Sm, general (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Includes portraits of Charles D. Sigobee, Bejmain Silliman, Thomas Y. Simons, Commander Edward Simpson, Commander William S. Sims, Charles H. Slack and Commodore John Drake Sloat.
    - Smith, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Includes portraits of Rear Admiral Joseph Smith, Lieutenant Joseph B. Smith, Commander Melancton Smith and Major General William F. Smith.
    - St-Sz, general (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Includes portraits of the Hon. Edwin M. Stanton, Commander Charles Steedman, H.K. Steever, Adolph Von Steinwehr, Rear Admiral R.N. Stembel, Baron Steuben, Commodore Charles Stewart, Yates Stirling, Commodore Robert Field Stockton, Benjamin Stoddert, General George Stoneman, Richard S. Storrs, Joseph Story, Oscar S. Straus, Rear Admiral Silas Stringham, Josiah Sturgis, Hon. Charles Sumner and Major General George Sykes.
    - T, general (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Includes portraits of William H. Taft, Captain Silas Talbot, Col. Benjamin Tallmadge, Commodore Josiah Tattnall, W.E. Taylor, Captain William Rogers Taylor, Zachary Taylor, Rev. Gilbert Tennent, Rear Admiral Henry K. Thatcher, General John Thomas, Charles Thomson, Captain James S. Thornton, Brigadier General Tilden, Daniel D. Thompkins, George E. Thrall, A.L. Tousard, Brevet Major General Nathaniel Towson, Sir Thomas Troubridge, Commander S.D. Trenchard, Captain John Trippe, Captain William Thomas Turner, Mark Twain and General Robert Ogden Tyler.
    - Truxtun, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Includes portraits of Commodore Thomas Truxtun and Lieutenant Commander W.J. Truxtun.
    - Tyler, John (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - U-V, general (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Includes portraits of Rear Admiral Frank B. Upham, Commander John H. Upham, Andrew Ure, William Aaron Van Vleck, Charles H. Venable, Fred Vilmar and Strong Vincent.
    - Wa-Wh, general (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Includes images of Commander Richard Wainwright, Philip S. Wales, Rear Admiral Henry Walke, Lieutenant Commander John G. Walker, Admiral Sir Provo Wallis, General Gouverneur K. Warren, Sir Peter Warren, Captain Lewis Warrington, Lieutenant William Henry Watson, Lieutenant Commander A. W. Weaver, Gideon Welles, C.J. White, Captain William Whitehead and Captain William C. Whittle.
    - Wi-Z, general (Box 15, Folder 12)
      Includes portraits of General Otho H. Williams, Reverend Miron Winslow, William Wirt, Captain H.A. Wise,General David Wooster, Major General John E. Wool, William J. Worth and Joseph S. Young.
    - Wilkes, Charles (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - WIlson, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Includes portraits of Alexander Wilson, Lieutenant Commander Byron Wilson and James Wilson.
    - Winslow, John A. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Wood, A-Z (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Lieutenant John Taylor Wood, William Maxwell Wood and Chief Engineer William W.W. Wood.
    - Worden, John L. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified - Individuals (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Group Portraits- Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Group Portraits- Officers & Sailors (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Group Portraits- Officers & Crew of the TSS City of New York (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Group Portraits- unidentified, aboard ships (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Naval Life (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Subseries I.10: Negatives
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Subseries I.8: Model Ships
      - Model Sailing Vessels- A-H (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Model Sailing Vessels- Dove of Maryland (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Model Sailing Vessels I-Z (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Model Sailing Vessels- Multiple Models (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Model Sailing Vessels- Unidentified (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Model Sailing Vessels- Details (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Model Steamships A-Z (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Model Steamships- Mary Powell (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Subseries I.11: Albums
    - John Paul Jones Scrapbook (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Sailing Vessels- 8 plates from unidentified book (Box 20, Folder 2)
      The following eight plates from unidentified book:
      Harpoon, August 8, 1892
      Alga, July 10, 1880
      Sayonara, September 8, 1891
      Gossoon, August 19, 1809
      Gorilla, July 13, 1893
      Verena, October 3, 1892
      Rosalind, August 18, 1886
      Eureka, September 18, 1891
    - Sailing Vessels- 20 plates from unidentified book (Box 20, Folder 3)
      The following twenty plates from an unidentified book: Plate IV- Galatea
      Plate V- Puritan
      Plate Vi- Genesta
      Plate VII- Priscilla
      Plate VIII- Atlantic
      Plate IX- Gracie
      Plate X- Bedouin
      Plate XVII- Cinderella
      Plate XIX- Titania
      Plate XXXIV- Gevalia
      Plate XXXV- Sachem
      Plate XXXVI- Iroquois
      Plate XXXVII- Ambassadress
      Plate XXXVIII- Em ELL EYE/Tartar
      Plate XXXIX- Mabel/Flora Lee
      Plate XL- Aline
      Plate XLI- Wendur
      Plate XLII- Irex
      Plate XLIII- May
      Plate XLVIII- Atlanta
    - Sailing Vessels Album- 6 albumen prints (Box 20, Folder 4)
      The following six albumen prints: Frolic
      Unidentified
      Queen Mab
      Miranda
    - Sailing Vessels Album (Box 20, Folder 5)
      The following twelve pages of photographs: Valkyrie
      Britannia/unidentified
      Calluna/unidentified
      Alisa
      Caress, May 17, 1893
      Vigilant, 1893/Dakotah
      Wenonah/Ailsa
      Valkyrie & Defender/ Defender
      Valkyrie & Defender, first race/ Valkyrie
      Vigilant & Britannia/ Vigilant reaching for Cowes, August 4
      Valkyrie
- Series II. Medium Format Flat Files
  Series II contains material between the sizes of 9 by 14 and 20 by 24 inches. Much of this series comes from clipping from illustrated newspapers and naval periodicals.
  - Subseries II.1: Sailing Vessels
    - A-M (Box Flat File, Folder FF1)
      This file includes the Currier and Ives lithographs The Gem of the Pacific and The Celebrated Ship Dreadnought as well as Nathaniel Currier’s The Celebrated Clipper Bark Grapeshot Belonging to Geo. Law Esq. N.Y.. This file also contains the aquatint The Brig Jane and Cutter Beaufoy on 20 February 1823.
    - America (Box Flat File, Folder FF 2)
    - N-Z (Box Flat File, Folder FF 3)
      This file contains photographs, clippings from periodicals and original lithographs such as Currier and Ives The Miniature Ship “Red, White, and Blue”, Clipper Ship Three Brothers and Nathaniel Currier’s Pilot Boat Wm. J. Romer.
    - Nina, Pinta and Santa Maria (Box Flat File, Folder FF 4)
    - Multiple Ships (Box Flat File, Folder FF 5)
      This file contains photographs, clippings from periodicals and original prints including Various Boats, Barks &c. used in the Rivers and on the Coasts of Peru in South America, engraved for Middleton’s Complete System of Geography. This file also contains several chromolithographs after works by Frederic S. Cozzens.
    - Unidentified ships (Box Flat File, Folder FF 6)
  - Subseries II.2: Steamships
    - A (Box Flat File, Folder FF 7)
      This file contains photographs, clippings from periodicals and original lithographs, including William Endicott’s Atlantic’s Return and Nathaniel Currier’s U.S.M. Steam Ship Arctic.
    - Albany (Box Flat File, Folder FF 8)
      - Q-S (Box Flat File, Folder FF 18)
    - B (Box Flat File, Folder FF 9)
      This file contains photographs, clippings from periodicals and original lithographs, including Currier and Ives’ The Narragansett Steamship Co’s Steamer Bristol of the Fall River Line, Nathaniel Currier’s U.S.M. Steam Ship Baltic, C. Bigot’s The British Queen and Senefelder’s Benjamin Franklin.
    - C (Box Flat File, Folder FF 10)
      This file contains photographs, advertisements for the American Steamship Circassian, images of the steamship Clermont and J.H. Bufford’s lithograph Camel Steam Tug, Lieut. J.A. Winslow, U.S.N. Inventor. Also includes photograph of Anchor Line Steamship “City of Rome” (used to transport Spanish prisoners of war in 1898) signed by the ship’s passengers.
    - D-F (Box Flat File, Folder FF 11)
    - G (Box Flat File, Folder FF 12)
    - Great Eastern (Box Flat File, Folder FF 13)
    - H-L (Box Flat File, Folder FF 14)
    - M (Box Flat File, Folder FF 15)
    - N (Box Flat File, Folder FF 16)
    - O-P (Box Flat File, Folder FF 17)
    - T-Z (Box Flat File, Folder FF 19)
    - Multiple & Unidentified ships (Box Flat File, Folder FF 20)